Guide to the Edith Wharton Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1895-1976; Series I; 9; (22 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Short Stories
      - "The Mummy Room": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 525)
      - "New England": holograph and typescript, corrected (incomplete) (Box 17, Folder 526-27)
      - "The News": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 528)
      - "Old Style"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 529)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 530)
      - "One Day": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 531)
      - "Opportunity": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 532)
      - "The Other Half": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 533)
      - "La Perla"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 534)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 535)
      - "Permanent Wave": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 536)
      - "Peter Elsom": typescript
        - First draft, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 537)
        - Second draft, corrected (Box 18, Folder 538)
        - Third draft, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 539)
      - "Pomegranate Seed"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 540)
        - French translation ("L'Appel De L'Au Dela"): typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 541-42)
      - "Princess Bluey of Blue Diamond Hall": holograph manuscript (Box 18, Folder 543)
      - "Rainbow Gold": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 544)
      - "Reality": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 545)
      - "Roman Fever": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 546)
      - "Solitude"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 547)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 548)
      - "The Spark": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 549-51)
      - "The Temperate Zone": holograph manuscript (incomplete), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 552)
      - "Tradition"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 553-56)
        - Synopsis, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 557)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 558-59)
      - "Two Careers"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 560)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 561)
      - "Velvet Ear-Pads"
        - Scenario, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 562)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 563)
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 564-66)
      - "The Venice Glass": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 567)
      - "Week-End": holograph manuscript, corrected (Box 18, Folder 568-69)
      - "The Word of Life": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 570)
      - "Writing a War Story"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 571)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 572)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 573)
        - Setting typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 574)
      - "Xingu": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 19, Folder 575-76)
      - "The Young Gentleman": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 577-78)
      - Miscellaneous fiction (fragments), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 579-80)
    - Essays
      - "Adventures with Books": holograph manuscript, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 581)
      - "Back to Compostala": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 582)
      - Benediction (by "Claude Silva"): "Foreward"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 583)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 584)
      - "Le Bourget d'Outremes": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 585-86)
      - "Character and Situation in the Novel"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 587-88)
        - Typescripts, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 589)
      - "A Cycle of Reviewing"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 590)
        - Typescript, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 591)
      - "December in a French Riviera Garden"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 592)
        - Typescripts with carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 593)
        - "Il dicembre in un giardino della Riviera francese" (Italian translation in an unknown hand), holograph manuscript (Box 19, Folder 594)
      - "Documentation in Fiction" ("Tendancies in Modern Fiction") holograph manuscript, corrected (Box 19, Folder 595)
      - "Fiction and Criticism"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, and photocopy (Box 19, Folder 596)
        - Typescript, corrected, and photocopy (Box 19, Folder 597)
      - "A French Riviera Garden in the Spring"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 598)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 599)
      - "A Further Glance": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 600)
      - "Gardening in France"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 601)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 602)
      - "In Morocco": correction sheet, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 603)
      - "Italy Again": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 604)
      - "A Motor-Flight Through Spain"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 605)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 606)
      - [National Institute of Arts and Sciences Speech on Accepting a Medal] typescript (incomplete) (Box 19, Folder 607)
      - "Olifant": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 608)
      - "Permanent Values in Fiction" holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 609)
      - "A Reconsideration of Marcel Proust" holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 610)
      - ["Sayings of HJ"]: holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 611)
      - "Talk to American Soldiers" (Lecture at the Soldiers and Sailors Club), typescript (Box 19, Folder 612)
      - "Visibility in Fiction"
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected (with related correspondence) (Box 19, Folder 613)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 614)
      - Whitman, Walt, Sketch of an Essay on, with notes, holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 615)
      - "William C. Brownell": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 616)
    - Plays
      - The Arch: holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 617)
      - The Banished God: holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 618)
      - The Children's Hour
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 619)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 620)
      - Crichton of Cluny: holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 621)
      - Kate Spain
        - Holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 622-23)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 624)
      - The Man of Genius
        - "Scenario": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 20, Folder 625)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 626)
      - Manon Lescaut: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 628-32)
      - The Necklace
        - Synopsis: holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 633)
        - First draft: holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 634)
        - Second draft: holograph manuscript, corrected (Box 20, Folder 635)
      - The Old Maid: dramatization by Zoë Akins
        - Typescript ("Revised Act One: English Production"), 1936 (Box 20, Folder 636)
        - Typescript ("Fourth Episode"), with related letter, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 637)
        - Program, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 638)
      - Pomegranate Seed
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 639)
        - Transcript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 640)
      - [Untitled]: holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 641)
    - Poems
      - "Adonis": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 642)
      - "All Saints": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 643)
      - "The 'Apollo of Marsyas' of Perugino"; "Phaedra": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 644)
      - "Beaulieu Wood": typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 645)
      - "La Belgique Ne Regrette Rien", 1915 Jan. (Box 20, Folder 646)
      - "Botticelli's Madonna in the Louvre": holograph manuscript and printed copy (Box 20, Folder 647)
      - "The Comrade": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 648)
      - "The Coming of the God": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 649)
      - "Death": typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 650)
      - "Destruction": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 651)
      - "The Dryad": holograph poem, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 652)
      - "Esther"
        - Holograph manuscript (with "Lucretia Buonvisi's Lover"), corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 653)
        - Typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 654)
      - "Ex Tenebris": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 655)
      - "Eyeless in Gaza": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 656)
      - "Finis": holograph manuscript
        See: "A Picture by Sebastiani", Box 21, folder 674
      - "The Great Blue Tent": typescript, 1915 Aug (Box 20, Folder 657)
      - "The Great Companions": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 658)
      - "The Heavenly Powers": holograph manuscript (with fragment titled "Restoration"), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 659)
      - "High Pasture": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 660)
      - "Intense Love's Utterance": holograph manuscript, 1881 Sep 13 (Box 20, Folder 661)
      - "Kithaeron": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 662)
      - "A Knock": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 663)
      - "Lucretia Buonvisi's Lover"
        See: "Esther," Box 20, folder 653
      - "Martyrdom": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 664)
      - "Mistral in the Marquis": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 665)
      - "The New Job": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 666)
      - "The New Litany": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 667)
      - "A November Day": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 668)
      - "The Old Pole Star": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 669)
      - "One Day": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 670)
      - "The Orestia": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 671)
      - "Orpheus": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 672)
      - "The Parting Day": printed copy, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 673)
      - "Phaedra": holograph manuscript
        See: "The 'Apollo and Marsyas' of Perugino", Box 20, folder 644
      - "A Picture By Sebastiani in the Cathedral at Murano" (with "Finis") holograph manuscript, 1895 (Box 21, Folder 674)
      - "Prologue": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 675)
      - "Rambouillet": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 676)
      - "Restoration": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 677)
      - "The Room": holograph manuscript, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 678)
      - "Sorrow's Sea": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 679)
      - "Summer Afternoon": holograph manuscript, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 680)
      - "Survival": holograph manuscript, 1908 Dec 4 (Box 21, Folder 681)
      - "Terminus": holograph copy by Morton Fullerton (with note from Marion Mainwaring, March 10, 1972), 1909 (Box 21, Folder 682)
      - "Terza Rima": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 683)
      - "The Tomb of Ilaria Giunigi at Lucca" holograph manuscript, 1889 (Box 21, Folder 684)
      - ["Thy Truth, O Lord"]: holograph manuscript (With letter from Evelyn Washburn and a copy of Wharton's "Easter" in Washburn's hand), 1881 (Box 21, Folder 685)
      - "A Torchbearer": typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 686)
        See also: George Dorr, Box 24, folder 753
      - "The Woman's Question": holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 687)
      - "Ye Romantic Ballad of Ye Picturesque Plums": holograph manuscript, 1875 May 31 (Box 21, Folder 688)
      - Untitled poems: holograph manuscripts, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 689-92)
      - Poems (fragments): holograph manuscripts, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 693)
    - Translations
      - The Joy of Living (Translation of Herman Suderman, Es Lebe Das Leben ): typescript, bound ("Mrs. Patrick Campbell's Prompt Book") (Box 21, Folder 694-98)
  - NOTEBOOKS
    - "Donnee Book", 1900 (Box 21, Folder 699)
    - "Notes", 1910-14 (Box 21, Folder 700)
    - "Subjects and Notes", 1918-23 (Box 22, Folder 701)
    - "Notes and Subjects", 1924-28 (Box 22, Folder 702-03)
- Personal Correspondence, Dates 1885-1937; Series II; 3.5; (8 boxes)
  Series II, Personal Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by surname of correspondent. With the exception of prominent persons (and letters from Edith Wharton), correspondents with fewer than three letters have been placed in "Letter" general files. The series combines correspondence both to and from Edith Wharton.
  - "A" general, 1905-34 (Box 23, Folder 704)
  - "B" general, 1905-19, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 705)
  - Barrés, Maurice, 1916 Apr 7 (Box 23, Folder 706)
  - Beerbohm, Max, 1915 (Box 23, Folder 707)
  - Berenson, Bernard, 1910-37 (Box 23, Folder 708-09)
  - Berenson, Mary, 1926-36 (Box 23, Folder 710)
  - Berry, Walter Van Rensselaer, 1898-1923 (Box 23, Folder 711-19)
  - Bigelow, William, 1910, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 720)
  - Binyon, Laurence, 1915 (Box 23, Folder 721)
  - Blashfield, Edwin H. Blashfield, Evangeline, 1899-1902 (Box 23, Folder 722)
  - Bosanquet, Theodora, 1910-15 (Box 23, Folder 723)
  - Bourget, Minnie, 1925, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 724)
  - Bourget, Paul, 1910, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 725)
    See also: Theodora Perry Tiffany, Box 30, folder 932
  - Bromfield, Louis, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 726)
  - Brownell, William Carey, 1909-26 (Box 23, Folder 727)
  - Burlingame, Edward L., 1905 Nov 4 (Box 23, Folder 728)
  - "C" general, 1928-31 (Box 23, Folder 729)
  - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick
    See: Theodora Perry Tiffany, Box 30, folder 932
  - Cambon, Jules M., 1916, 1918 (Box 23, Folder 730)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel
    See: The Literary Review, Box 37, folder 1140
  - Chanler, Margaret ("Daisy"), 1902-33 (Box 24, Folder 731-41)
  - Clark, Sir Kenneth M., 1936-37 (Box 24, Folder 742)
  - Clark, Lady Elizabeth
  - Claudel, Paul, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 743)
  - Conrad, Joseph, 1912-17 (Box 24, Folder 744)
  - Crawford, Francis Marion, 1899 Apr 2 (Box 24, Folder 745)
  - "D" general, 1905-36 (Box 24, Folder 746)
  - De La Mare, Walter, 1936-37 (Box 24, Folder 747)
  - Deland, Margaret, 1899 Oct 20 (Box 24, Folder 748)
  - Dimnet, Ernest, 1932-35 (Box 24, Folder 749)
  - D'Indy, Vincent, 1916 Sep 22 (Box 24, Folder 750)
  - Dix, Morgan, 1902, 1905 (Box 24, Folder 751)
  - Doane, William Croswell, 1907 Nov 18 (Box 24, Folder 752)
  - Dorr, George B., 1902-06 (Box 24, Folder 753)
  - Dumaine, Jacques, 1918, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 754)
  - Dunsany, Edward John, 1911 Jan 19 (Box 24, Folder 755)
  - "E" general, 1930-33 (Box 24, Folder 756)
  - "F" general, 1906, 1910 (Box 24, Folder 757)
  - Fairchild, Sally, [1915?] Nov 17 (Box 24, Folder 758)
  - Farrand, Beatrix Jones, 1912-37 (Box 25, Folder 759-66)
  - Farrand, Max, 1914-36 (Box 25, Folder 767-68)
  - Fitch, Clyde, 1907-[09?] (Box 25, Folder 769)
    See also: Box 36, folder 1105
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (copy only), 1925 (Box 25, Folder 770)
  - French, Daniel Chester, 1905 Nov 12 (Box 25, Folder 771)
  - Frederich, J., 1935-37 (Box 25, Folder 772)
  - Fuller, Henry Blake, 1902 Mar 27 (Box 25, Folder 773)
  - Fullerton, William Morton, [1907] Oct 19 (Box 25, Folder 774)
  - "G" general, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 775)
  - Galsworthy, John, 1915, 1918 (Box 25, Folder 776)
  - Gide, André, 1916-19, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 777)
  - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1902-09, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 778)
  - Gillet, Louis, 1923-37, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 779-81)
  - Gillet, Louisette, 1931-32, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 782)
  - Gosse, Edmund, 1908-25 (Box 25, Folder 783-84)
  - Gouraud, Henri-Joseph-Etienne, 1918 (Box 25, Folder 785)
  - Graham, Robert Cunninghame, 1934 (Box 25, Folder 786)
  - Grant, Robert, 1905-39 (Box 25, Folder 787-93)
  - Gross, Catherine, 1914, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 794)
  - "H" general, 1905-37 (Box 26, Folder 795)
  - Hagner, Isabella, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 796)
  - Hardy, Thomas, 1915 (Box 26, Folder 797-98)
  - Hawkes, Eva, 1915-18 (Box 26, Folder 799)
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1905 Dec 19 (Box 26, Folder 800)
  - Housman, Laurence, 1936 Sep 19 (Box 26, Folder 801)
  - Howells, William Dean, 1900-19 (Box 26, Folder 802)
  - Hudson, Elizabeth
    See: Simmons, Frank Ronald, Box 30, folder 924
  - Hugh Smith, John, 1908-38 (Box 26, Folder 803-10)
  - Humbert, Georges-Louis, 1915-16 (Box 26, Folder 811)
  - James, Henry, 1900-09 (Box 26, Folder 812-20)
  - James, Henry, 1910-15 (Box 27, Folder 821-32)
  - James, Margaret, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 833)
  - James, William, 1910 (Box 27, Folder 834)
  - Joffre, Joseph J., 1918 Dec 13 (Box 28, Folder 835)
  - Jones, Mary Cadwalader, 1903-35 (Box 28, Folder 836-62)
    See also: Box 51, folder 1558
  - Jusserand, Jean Adrien, 1916 Apr 7 (Box 28, Folder 863)
  - "K" general, 1913-29 (Box 28, Folder 864)
  - Kipling, Rudyard, 1915, 1923 (Box 28, Folder 865-66)
  - "L" general, 1902-34 (Box 29, Folder 867)
  - Lapsley, Gaillard, 1916-31 (Box 29, Folder 868)
  - Lebaudy, Pierre, 1926 Mar 2 (Box 29, Folder 869)
  - La Gallienne, Richard
  - Lodge, George Cabot, [1905] (Box 29, Folder 870)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1909, 1919 (Box 29, Folder 871)
  - Loti, Pierre, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 872)
  - Lubbock, Percy, 1913-18 (Box 29, Folder 873)
  - Lyautey, Inez, 1918 (Box 29, Folder 874)
  - "M" general, 1905-37 (Box 29, Folder 875)
  - MacCarthy, Desmond, [1933?] Mar 26 (Box 29, Folder 876)
  - McCook, Miss, [1921 Jan 6?] (Box 29, Folder 877)
  - McCutcheon, George Barr, 1905 Oct 31 (Box 29, Folder 878)
  - Mariano, Elisabeth ("Nicky"), 1933, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 879)
  - Martin, Miss, 1917 May 17 (Box 29, Folder 880)
  - Masefield, John, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 881)
  - Meynell, Alice, 1915 Aug 16 (Box 29, Folder 882)
  - Minturn, Robert S., 1916 (Box 29, Folder 883)
  - Mitchell, Silas Weir, 1905 Nov 2 (Box 29, Folder 884)
    See also: Box 61, folder 1740
  - Morris, George L. K., n.d. (Box 29, Folder 885)
  - "N" general, 1905-30 (Box 29, Folder 886)
  - Navarro, Antonio F. de, 1899, 1902 (Box 29, Folder 887)
  - Nicholson, [Ronald?], 1927-29 (Box 29, Folder 888)
  - Noailles, Anna E., Countess de, 1915-16 (Box 29, Folder 889)
  - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1907-08 (Box 29, Folder 890)
  - Norton, Sara ("Sally"), 1899-1913 (Box 29, Folder 891-904)
  - Norton, Sara ("Sally"), 1914-22 (Box 30, Folder 905-08)
  - Paget, Violet ("Vernon Lee"), 1902-33 (Box 30, Folder 909)
  - Pasteur, Louis (autograph note), 1885 Apr 10 (Box 30, Folder 910)
  - Pershing, John J., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 911)
  - Popham-Lobb, R., 1926-27 (Box 30, Folder 912)
  - "R" general, 1899-1937, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 913)
  - Read, Herbert, 1934 Jun 18 (Box 30, Folder 914)
  - Rhinelander, Philip M., 1927 (Box 30, Folder 915)
  - Rhinelander, Philip Newbold, 1918 (Box 30, Folder 916)
  - Richardson, William K., 1913 (Box 30, Folder 917)
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1932 Mar 10 (Box 30, Folder 918)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1915, 1918 (Box 30, Folder 919)
  - "S" general, 1909-37 (Box 30, Folder 920)
  - Saintsbury, George, 1913 Dec 11 (Box 30, Folder 921)
  - Sargent, John Singer, 1911-15 (Box 30, Folder 922)
  - Sheldon, Edward, 1923-31 (Box 30, Folder 923)
    See also: Box 39, folder 1191
  - Simmons, Frank Ronald, 1918 (Box 30, Folder 924)
  - Smith, Logan Pearsall, 1926 Feb 2 (Box 30, Folder 925)
  - Sturgis, Howard Overing, 1904-17 (Box 30, Folder 926-27)
  - Suarès, Andre, 1915 Aug 15 (Box 30, Folder 928)
  - "T" general, 1901-34 (Box 30, Folder 929)
  - Taillandier, Madeleine Saint René, 1916-33 (Box 30, Folder 930)
  - Thayer, William Roscoe, 1905 (Box 30, Folder 931)
  - Tiffany, Theodora Perry, 1901, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 932)
  - Trench, Herbert, 1915 Aug 18 (Box 30, Folder 933)
  - Trevelyan, Sir George Otto, 1923 (Box 30, Folder 934)
  - Updike, Daniel Berkeley, 1913, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 935)
  - "W" general, 1910-34 (Box 30, Folder 936)
  - Ward, Mary A., 1915 Aug 12 (Box 30, Folder 937)
  - Washburn, Emelyn, 1930, 1935 (Box 30, Folder 938)
  - Wells, H. G., [1915 Aug 13] (Box 30, Folder 939)
  - Wendell, Barrett, 1899, 1913 (Box 30, Folder 940)
  - Wharton, Edward R., 1907-12, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 941)
  - Wharton, Nancy ("Nannie"), 1909-10 (Box 30, Folder 942)
  - Wharton, William, 1911 (Box 30, Folder 943)
  - Wilcox, Ella Wheeler, 1918 Apr 8 (Box 30, Folder 944)
  - Winthrop, Egerton, 1913 (Box 30, Folder 945)
  - Wister, Owen, 1906 Jan (Box 30, Folder 946)
  - Yeats, William Butler, 1915 (Box 30, Folder 947)
  - Unidentified, 1906-34 (Box 30, Folder 948)
- Professional Correspondence, 1905-37; Series III; 4; (9 boxes)
  Series III., Professional Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by name of the individual, company, or institution. Correspondents with fewer than three items are placed in "Letter" general files.
  - "A" general, 1920-36 (Box 31, Folder 949)
  - Affolter (Librairie Auguste Fontaine), 1917-33 (Box 31, Folder 950-54)
    See also: Augoyat, Jean, Box 31, folder 964
  - Alfossa, P., 1922-24 (Box 31, Folder 955)
  - Albatross (J. Holryd-Reece), 1932-36 (Box 31, Folder 956)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1928-37 (Box 31, Folder 957-58)
  - American Library in Paris, 1922-36 (Box 31, Folder 959)
  - The American Magazine, 1919-20 (Box 31, Folder 960)
  - American Play Company, Inc., 1921 (Box 31, Folder 961)
  - Anglin-Hull, Margaret, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 962)
  - Appleton, D.
    See: D. Appleton and Co., Box 33, folder 1028
  - Art et Industrie, 1927-31 (Box 31, Folder 963)
  - Augoyat, Jean (Librairie Auguste Fontaine), 1927-31 (Box 31, Folder 964-65)
    See also: Affolter, Box 31, folder 950
  - Authors' League of America, 1920-30 (Box 31, Folder 966-67)
  - Authors' Syndicate, Limited
    See: Smith and Earle, Box 39, folder 1193
  - "B" general, 1911-36 (Box 31, Folder 968-70)
  - Bain, James, 1918-37 (Box 31, Folder 971-83)
  - Bernheim, Andre, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 984)
  - Libreria Bettesti et Tumminelli, 1928-32 (Box 32, Folder 985)
  - Bloch, Camille, 1929-37 (Box 32, Folder 986-88)
  - Bois, Jeanne, 1924-25 (Box 32, Folder 989)
  - Bridges, Robert
    See: Charles Scribner's Sons, Box 32, folder 998
  - Brockhaus, F. A., 1933 (Box 32, Folder 990)
  - Brown, E. K., 1930 (Box 32, Folder 991)
  - Burgess, Gellett
    See: Author's League of America, Box 31, folder 966
  - "C" general, 1920-35 (Box 32, Folder 992-93)
  - Carlyle Straub, 1936-37 (Box 32, Folder 994)
  - Cassell and Company, 1926-37 (Box 32, Folder 995)
  - The Century Company, 1927-29 (Box 32, Folder 996)
  - Charles Frohman Inc. (Empire Theater), 1928 (Box 32, Folder 997)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1905-37 (Box 32, Folder 998-1007)
  - Cinotti, Henri, 1934-35 (Box 32, Folder 1008)
  - Clemens, Cyril
    See: International Mark Twain Society, Box 37, folder 1115
  - Cobden-Sanderson, Richardson, 1924-28 (Box 32, Folder 1009)
  - The Colophon, 1931-35 (Box 32, Folder 1010)
  - Cosmopolitan, 1919-37 (Box 32, Folder 1011)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1919-28 (Box 32, Folder 1012-17)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1929-36 (Box 33, Folder 1018-25)
  - "D" general, 1920-36 (Box 33, Folder 1026-27)
  - D. Appleton and Co., 1916-23 (Box 33, Folder 1028-40)
  - D. Appleton and Co., 1924-28 (Box 34, Folder 1041-57)
  - D. Appleton and Co., 1929-34 (Box 35, Folder 1058-77)